A Guide to the Black Women at Virginia Tech Oral History Project, 1995-present
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Black Women at Virginia Tech Oral History Project, 1995-present
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1995-0266
3 Cubic Feet 3 boxes
Access Restrictions
The majority of the collection is open to research. Restrictions on access to specific files or types of files are noted at the the item level in the contents list of the collection below.
Alternate Form Available
Several of the interviews in this collection have been digitized and are available online with transcripts. Links to individual interviews are included at the item level in the contents list below.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Black Women at Virginia Tech Oral History Project is a multi-phase research and educational collaborative program of the University Libraries and the Women's Center at Virginia Tech. This project is an on- going program that involves the identification of the first black women students, staff, and faculty at Virginia Tech and the collection of their oral history narratives.
Scope and Contents
The interviews focus on the entry experience of the individual into the Virginia Tech community and the interviewees' perceptions of the climate and attitudes within the university community, particularly as pertains to race and gender. The materials in this collection includes cassette tapes, DAT tapes, and transcripts of interviews with some of the first black women students at Virginia Tech (Jacquelyn Butler Blackwell, Marguerite Harper Scott, and Linda Edmunds Turner); Marva Felder Davis, first black homecoming queen; Cheryl Butler McDonald, first black woman in the Corps of Cadets; and Elaine Carter, catalyst of the project and doctoral candidate at Virginia Tech. Interviews were conducted by Elaine Dowe Carter and University Archivist Tamara Kennelly.
Transcripts of interviews with students and with two staff members (Cora McDaniel Pack and Rhonda Miller Rogers) are available either in print. Transcripts and audio of several interviews are available online.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Faculty; University Archives; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University; Women -- History
Genre and Form Terms
Oral histories (document genres)
Contents List
- 3.5" Floppy Disks (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Disks, n.d., two 3.5" floppy disks labeled "Interview with Jackie Butler Blackwell, Elaine Carter," and "Black Women's History Project Interviews (Copies) MAC-Word"
- Project Documents, 1997-2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Blackwell, Jacquelyn Butler, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Alternate Form Available
  April 29, 1994, interview and transcript online
  Blackwell, Jacquelyn Butler, 1995- 1996, copy of permission form and interview transcript
- Blackwell, Jackie Butler, April 29, 1994; September 28, 1995 (Box 2)
  Interview on 29 April 1994; original tape and 1 copy; interview on 28 September 1995; original tape and 1 copy
- Carter, Elaine, October 19,1995; December 7, 1995; December 12, 1995 (Box 2)
  Access Restriction
  Transcripts from the December 7, 1995, and December 12, 1995, interviews may only be accessed through the Special Collections reading room. These transcripts may not be copied, nor can Special Collections provide copies to researchers through the mail or via email (digital files are not available). The audio file for this interview is not available to the public.
  October 19, 1995, interview and transcript available online
  Interview on 19 October 1995; 1 tape. Interview on 7 December 1995; 2 tapes. Interview on 12 December 1995; 2 tapes
- Felder, Marva (Carter Davis), 1983-1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Interview and digitized transcript
  Felder, Marva (Carter Davis), 1983-1999, variety of items relating to Marva Felder, such as copies of interview transcripts, pages from the Bugle yearbook, two 3.5" floppy disks ("Marva Felder Interview" and "Marva2.txt"), and permission form
- Davis, Marva, March 27, 1999 (Box 2)
  Interview on 27 March 1999; 2 cassette and 1 DAT tape, and 2 cassette and 1 DAT tape copies
- Hairston, Fredi, 1996-2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Interview and transcript available online
- Higgins, Dr. Laverna (Fredi Hairston), September 28, 2000 (Box 2)
  Interview on 28 September 2000; interviewed by Tamara Kennelly; 2 tapes
- Hoyle, Linda Paulette Adams, 1968-1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Access Restriction (Audio File)
  Transcripts of this interview are available online. The audio file is not available to the public.
  Transcripts of this interview are available online.
  Hoyle, Linda Paulette Adams, 1968-1997, copies of correspondence and a web page
- MacDonald, Cheryl Butler, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Interview and transcript availabe online
  MacDonald, Cheryl Butler, 1998, copies of permission form, interview transcript, and 3.5" floppy disk labeled "Interview w/ Cheryl Butler McDonald "
- MacDonald, Cheryl Butler, November 28, 1998 (Box 3)
  Interview on 28 November 1998; interviewed by Tamara Kennelly; 2 cassette and 1 DAT tape, and 1 DAT tape copy
- Pack, Cora McDamel, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Pack, Cora McDamel, 1997, copy of permission form and interview transcript
- Rogers, Rhonda Miller, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Rogers, Rhonda Miller, 1997, copy of permission form and interview transcript
- Scott, Marguerite Harper, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Scott, Marguerite Harper, 1996, copy of permission form and interview transcripts
- Scott, Marguerite Harper, March 2, 1996 (Box 3)
  Interview on 2 March 1996; 2 original tapes and 2 copies
- Turner, Linda Edmonds, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Turner, Linda Edmonds, 1996-1997, copy of permission form and interview transcript
- Turner, Linda Edmonds, March 2, 1996 (Box 3)
  Interview on 2 March 1996; interviewed by Elaine Carter; 2 original tapes and 2 copies
- Linda Edmonds Scrapbook, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Linda Edmonds Scrapebook, c.1967, photocopies of items from her scrapbook